Finding Aid for Robert M. Warner Papers, 1945-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Speeches
  - Immigration History Research Conference (Box 32)
  - Michigan Student Life (Box 32)
  - Michigan Founding Date (Box 32)
  - Muskingum Dinner (Box 32)
  - Park Library Dedication CMU 2002 (Box 32)
  - SILS Speeches (Box 32)
  - Women at the University of Michigan (Box 32)
- Scrapbooks and Scrapbook Materials
  The Scrapbook and Scrapbook Materials series (.25 linear feet) consists of fourteen folders with letters, photos, publicity and write-ups for lectures and achievements, dinner and conference, greeting cards, awards and certificates of appreciation, and a file of Jane's dinner party menus. This series also contains a folder of invitations and personal letters from President Ford and newspaper clippings about Ford and the Ford Library. The series covers Warner's time in Muskingum College (1945-1949), one folder of pre-1980 material and items from 1989-2000. Scrapbook materials for 1980-1988 can be found in eight outsized Scrapbooks. An index is located at the beginning of each volume and there is a complete subject index on note cards.
  - Muskingum 1945-1949 (including class notes) (Box 33)
  - Pre 1980 (Box 33)
  - Volume 1 1980-1988 (Volume 1)
  - Volume 2 1980-1988 (Volume 2)
  - Volume 3 1980-1988 (Volume 3)
  - Volume 4 1980-1988 (Volume 4)
  - Volume 5 1980-1988 (Volume 5)
  - Volume 6 1980-1988 (Volume 6)
  - Volume 7 1980-1988 (Volume 7)
  - Volume 8 1980-1988 (Volume 8)
  - Volumes 1-8 Index (on index cards) (Box 33)
  - 1989-2006 (Box 33)
  - Gerald R. Ford Items (Box 33)
  - Awards (Box 33)
  - Jane's Menus 1967-1981 (Box 33)
- Audio-Visual
  The Audio-Visual series (4.25 linear feet) consists of two sub-series: Photographs and Audio.
  - Photos
    The Photographs subseries (3.75 linear feet) contains collections of slides, photo albums and snapshots from various professional trips and celebrations. Of interest are slides of the construction of the Bentley Library, professional trips to China, Japan, Russia, Poland, and Scandinavia. The series contains one box of reproductions of architectural drawings of proposals for the National Archives Buildings. There are also folders/pockets of photographs from functions at the national archives and professional shots for publications publicity.
    - Bentley Library Album: The President's House, Greenhills Graduation, and The Bentley Library's Dedication (Box 33)
      (album created July, 1980)
    - Bush Library November, 1997 negatives and prints in sleeve (Box 33)
    - Gerald Ford at the Bentley Library 1977 (Box 33)
    - Japanese Trip 1987 KIT-LC International Seminar, 6 volumes (Box 33)
    - Leningrad and Moscow Trip (slides) (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Archives II construction (Box 33)
      - Early Bentley Construction (Box 33)
      - Gerald Ford (Box 33)
      - Helen Snoke Retirement (Box 33)
      - Ida C. Brown, MHC Librarian (Box 33)
      - MHC in Rackham Building (Box 33)
      - NARA 1981-1982 (Box 33)
      - NARA Portrait Unveiling at Bentley 1989 (Box 33)
      - Retirement from SILS (Box 33)
      - Richard Hunt Sculptor (Box 33)
      - University Library Office (Box 33)
      - Winchell Hall Office (Box 33)
    - National Archives Building Drawings: Pope Drawings and Early Proposals (Box 34)
    - National Archives Function December 1987 (loose prints in sleeve) (Box 34)
    - National Archives Photographs (Box 34)
    - Publication Photographs (Box 34)
    - R. Hunt Electra Springs (slides) (Box 34)
    - Russia and Poland October-November, 1995 (album) (Box 34)
    - Scandinavia and Russia 1972 Germany (Dusseldorf) and England (Box 34)
    - Various Photos (Box 35)
    - 175 President's Forum September 17, 1992, 1 volumes (Box 35)
      (includes program and personal letter from Jim Duderstadt)
    - China Trip, Nanjing Archives, Beijing Archives, Other Archives 1986, 3 volumes (Box 35)
    - China Trip 1986 (Jane) (Box 35)
    - Photograph Binders, documenting professional functions and accomplishments 1945-1999 (bulk dates 1980-1995, 5 volumes (Box 36)
  - Audio Recordings (Box 37)
    The Audio subseries (.5 linear feet) contains 69 cassettes and 5 mini cassettes. The cassettes range from the early 1970s to 2004. The earliest cassettes are unprofessional recordings of Warner on radio programs speaking about the archival profession. Many of the cassettes are diary entries that were later transcribed (see the Diary Series) and that are slightly different from the transcription. The diary recordings after 2000 were never transcribed. Other tapes are lectures, speeches, family recordings (Warner Christmas 1971), Concerts, and minutes from committee meetings he attended.
    - Audio Cassettes Tapes, 69 audiocassettes; 5 audiocassetes mini cassettes (Box 37)
      [RESTRICTED until July 1 2017 ]
- University of Michigan
  - Class Register History 577 (Box 38)
    [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2043 ]
  - Recommendation letters (Box 38)
  - Beth Yakel PhD proposal (Box 38)
    [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2075 ]
Key to Correspondence Symbols of Selected National Archives Officials
N Archivist of the U.S. Robert M. Warner
NA Executive Director John J. Landers, Claudine Weiher
NB Special Assistant to the Archivist John Byrne
NC Office of Federal Records Centers George Scaboo, David Peterson
NCO Center Operations Division Linda N. Brown
NCD Center Disposition Division Thomas W. Wadlow
ND Deputy Archivist Ed Weldon, George Scaboo
NE Office of Educational Programs Albert Meise, Linda N. Brown
NF Office of the Federal Register Ernest L. Galdi, J.E.B. Byrns
NK Preservation Officer Alan Calmes
NL Office of Presidential Libraries James O'Neill
NLN Nixon Presidential Materials Project James Hastings
NN Office of the National Archives James Moore
NNR Machine-readable Archives Division Charles M. Dollar
NP National Historic Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC) Frank Burke
NR Office of Records and Information Management Forest Williams
NS Assistant to Archivist Robert Brookhart